Today's
Slogan
Yuri had the other half of the diary.
日記の半分は百合さんが持ってたんだ
なら　もう半分はやっぱり真砂子が持ってるんだな
Masako must have the other half, then.
Someone is targeting you.
奪いに来た女ってのも
She must be the woman who came to steal the other half.
多分
Probably.
What is Yuri Tokikago after?
時籠百合の目的は
Takoyaki powder
運命を乗り換えるんだってさ
She says she's going to transfer fate.
お前　それ信じたのか
Do you actually believe that?
まさか
No way!
けど　日記を揃えて　運命を乗り換えられるなら
But, if it's possible to transfer fate by completing the diary...
もしかして　ひまりが元気になる事だって
Maybe Himari can even get better.
馬鹿な事を言うな　ひまりにはあの薬があるだろう
Don't be absurd.
Himari has that medicine.
でも　高いんだろう
But, isn't it expensive?
It's not something you should be worried about.
余計な心配するな　治療代は俺がなんとかする
I'll come up with the money for treatment somehow.
だから　お前はいつも通り笑ってろ
So, you just keep smiling as you always do.
いいな
Got it?
うん
Yes.
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
交わらないイマジナリー
majiwaranai imaginary
The Imaginary and the Real can never mingle
回転木馬宙を舞って
kaiten mokuba chuu wo matte
The merry-go-round twirls into the air
戦いの幕を切って落とす
tatakai no maku wo kitte otosu
As the curtain of war is torn open
秘め事明かすホーリーナイト
himegoto akasu holy night
The Holy Night for divulging secrets
真夜中開く窓
mayonaka hiraku mado temaneku nazo no koe
My window opens at night and a mysterious voice beckons
手招く謎の声
深紅のカーテンを翻して
shinku no curtain wo hirugaeshite hohoemi kakusu
A crimson curtain conceals the smile
微笑み隠す
少年よ我に帰れ
shounen yo ware ni kaere
Boys, come back to me
特急列車乗っちゃって
tokkyuu ressha nocchate
I ended up getting on the midnight express
ネパーランドに連れてって
neverland ni tsuretette
Take me away to Neverland
一切合切奪ってよ
issai gassai ubatte yo
Steal away everything I have
後ろ指さされたって
ushiro yubi sasaretatte
I don't care if you talk behind my back
一目散に逃げちゃっていいよ
ichimokusan ni nigechatte iiyo
I'll just run away at full speed
全部お気に召すまま
zenbu oki ni mesu mama
Do as you please
少年少女輪になって
shounen shoujo wa ni natte
The boys and girls form a ring
伸ばした手は空を切って落ちる
nobashita te wa kuu wo kitte ochiru
Extended hands cut down through the air
回り始めるディステニー
mawari hajimeru destiny
Destiny begins to turn
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：hunter 翻译:草泥马 校对:冷漠的风  木落 时间轴:wcaster 压制:wcaster
To'oh General Hospital
わー　おー　固まってきた
Wow!
Ooh! They're getting crispy.
Okay, just watch!
よーし　見てろよ
凄い　冠ちゃん引っ繰り返すの上手
Amazing! You're so good at turning them over!
Yup!
まーな　これだけは俺の方がうまい
I'm better than him at this.
Alert us if someone's coming!
誰が来たら　すぐに教えろよ
バレたら　間違えなくできんだぞ
We'll be banned from visiting for sure if we get caught!
分かってるよ
I know!
ったく　僕だって引っ繰り返すの超得意なのに
Geez! I'm also super good at turning them over...
Here, Himari.
ほら　ひまり
わー　いい匂い
Oh! They smell so good.
熱いから　気を付けろよ
Be careful, they're hot.
いただきます
Let's eat!
おいひい
They're delicious!
Eating takoyaki as a family is the best!
やっぱり家族で食べるタコ焼きは最高だね
We figured you were probably sick of hospital food by now.
病院の飯にも飽きたと思ってな　どんどん食べろよ
Eat as many as you want.
うん
Okay!
僕の分も残しといてよ
Leave some for me!
うん　うまいな
They're good!
くそー
Damn it!
なんで僕ばっかこんな役を
Why do I always get the lame duty?
はい　晶ちゃん
Here, Sho.
You like yours with plenty of green seaweed, right?
晶ちゃんは青海苔たっぷりだったよね
You're so kind, Himari!
ひまり　優しい
いいんだ　ひまり
Don't worry about him, Himari.
晶馬は余った天かすで十分だから
Just leave him some leftover crumbs.
冠葉こそ紅生姜の汁でも飲んでりゃいいじゃん
You can just drink the pickled ginger sauce then!
もう　冠ちゃんも晶ちゃんもそんなことで喧嘩しないの
Sheesh, don't fight over something so silly, you two!
二人とも子供なんだから
You're both acting like children!
ご馳走様でした
Thanks for the food!
ああ　お腹いっぱい
I'm stuffed!
よかった　ひまりが元気になってくれて
I'm glad you're all better.
最近すっごく調子がいいんだ
I've been in tip-top shape lately.
あの薬のおかげかな
I guess it's all thanks to that medicine.
眞悧先生もね　この分ならもうすぐ退院できるかもって
Dr. Sanetoshi says I can be released from the hospital soon.
本当
Really?
Yeah!
うん　眞悧先生がいうんだから　きっと大丈夫だよ
You can believe Dr. Sanetoshi's words.
じゃあ　次は退院祝いにすき焼きだな
When you get out, let's go for sukiyaki to celebrate!
え　やった
Really? Yay!
あ　そうだ　二人に聞きたいことがあったんだ
Oh, right.
There's something I wanted to ask you two.
Tada!
ジャン
えー　今度は何
Oh! What is it this time?
セーター
Sweaters!
いよいよ　大物にチャレンジか
You're finally taking on the challenge of a big item!
ねえ　この色　どうかな
What do you think about this color?
いいんじゃない
I guess it's all right.
ああ　でも　ひまりにはちょっと地味かな
But, maybe it's a bit too dull for you.
あ　ううん　あたしのじゃなくて
No, it's not for me.
えっと　男の人のなんだ　お礼にと思って
It's... for a man.
A thank you gift.
え　男の人
What? A man?!
What do you think, Kan?
ね　冠ちゃんはどう
I guess it's fine.
いいんじゃねぇの　俺の趣味じゃねぇけど
Not my taste, but for that guy...
あいつになら
もう　何やってんだよ
Geez, what are you doing?
ちゃんとゴミはゴミ箱へだろう
Garbage goes in the garbage bin, remember?
ねえ　ひまり　それって誰にあげるの
Hey, Himari...
Who is it for?
Could it be...
もしかして　なんて　ないか
Nah! It couldn't be, right?
内緒
It's a secret.
内緒だよ
I'm not telling!
Himari is all better now.
ひまり　元気になったよな
Yeah.
Soon, the three of us can live together again.
もうすぐまた三人で暮らせるんだ
これでやっと普通に戻れるのかな
I wonder if we can finally go back to normal.
変な帽子に指図されたり
No more weird hat ordering us around,
訳の分からない日記を追い回したりする必要のない
and it won't be necessary to chase some weird diary down.
No, it's necessary.
いや　必要だ
What?
生存戦略
Survival Strategy!
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Night
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Fight
I'm just a Rock'n Roll Man
We're just a Rock'n Roll BAND
俺たちは道なりに　走り続けてきた
標識だらけの道を飛ばし続けていく
幾つもの町を抜け　歌い続けてきた
腑抜け野郎共を煽り続けていく
長い長い冬が溶けても風が吹く
今も今も激しく風が吹く
Imagine!
Listen, you lowlifes who will never amount to anything.
きっと何者にもなれないお前たちに告げる
また告げるのかよ
Not this again!
もうお前いらないって
We don't need you anymore!
貴様ら　己の任務を忘れたか
Have you imbeciles forgotten your duty?
There is not a second to be wasted.
もはや一刻の猶予もならぬ
ピングドラムを手に入れるのだ
Obtain the Penguin Drum.
で　ピングドラムってのは　やっぱりあの日記のことなのか
So, Penguin Drum really is that diary?
な
No–
Not telling.
内緒
久しぶりに出て来てそれかよ
You showed up for the first time in ages just to tell us that?
But I'll tell you something important as a bonus.
だが　ボーナスに一つ大事な事を教えてやる
If you continue to neglect the Penguin Drum,
このままビングドラムを放置すれば
Someone in your family will suffer a terrible punishment.
お前達家族の誰かが　大きな罰を受けることになるだろう
罰
Punishment?
なんのことだ
What do you mean?
お前達が一番大切にしている者が損なわれるのだ
What you treasure the most will be lost.
What we treasure the most...
一番大切なもの
なんなんだよ
What's your problem?
We were just enjoying takoyaki as a family.
家族で楽しくタコ焼き食べてたのに　いきなりそんなこと言われて
Do you really expect us to just go "Oh, okay" to such an absurd demand?
はい　そうですかって聞けるわけないだろう
生存戦略　しましょうか
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.
俺じゃ　だめなんだろう
It can't be me, right?
もう　俺にはひまりを救うことはできないんだろう
I can't be the one to save Himari anymore, right?
You can do it.
お前にはできる
わらわには　それが分かる
I can tell.
Because Penguin Drum is...
なぜなら　ピングドラムとは　それはお前の
It is your...
俺には無理だ
I... can't.
日記を高倉晶馬に貸して欲しいって言われたわ
Shoma Takakura wanted me to lend him the diary.
妹の命がどうとか
He was saying something strange about his sister's life and penguins.
ペンギンがどうとか　妙なことを言ってたけど
そう
He did?
Obviously, I turned him down.
勿論断ったわよ　あたし達とは目的が違うもの
His goal is different from ours.
それにあの子達　この日記のホントの価値さえよく分かってないみたい
Not to mention, those kids can't appreciate the true value of this diary.
この世界でそれを知っているのは　君と僕だけだよ
You and I are the only ones in the world who do.
そうね
Yes.
I still can't forgive members of Takakura Family.
私　やっぱり高倉家の人間を許すことは出来ないわ
まだ　君はそんな事を
You're still on about that?
もう昔の事じゃないか
It's all in the past.
それにあの子達が直接手を下したわけじゃない
And it's not like they're directly responsible for it.
リンゴちゃんは高倉晶馬のことが好きなのよ
Ringo is in love with Shoma Takakura.
知ってる
I know.
Are you okay with that?
いいの
Ringo is Ringo.
リンゴちゃんはリンゴちゃんだ　桃果じゃない
She's not Momoka.
I know that!
分かってるわよ　そんなこと
But...
でも
The sins of the parents aren't shared by the children.
実行犯と家族は別だよ
僕はもう彼らに特別な感情は抱いてない
I no longer have particular feelings toward them.
You're going to forgive them?
許すの
高倉は罪もない大勢の人の命を奪ったのよ
The Takakuras took the lives of many innocent people!
桃果はそれを止めようとして
Momoka tried to stop that, and...
Regret and hatred won't bring anyone back.
悔やんで　恨んで
取り返せるものなんて何もないんだ
You sure are a man of integrity.
ご立派な人格者だこと
あなたは昔からいつもそう
You always have been.
僕だって　桃果の事を忘れたわけじゃないさ
I haven't forgotten about Momoka, either.
How could either of us forget?
忘れられるはずないんだ　僕達が
Tabuki and Yuri - The Day We Played with Momoka - By that memorable pond - Fate that binds us. Momoka was our everything. Those days we spent with her were always so bright.
あ　鳥
Ah! It's a bird!
大丈夫　きっと飛べるよ
Don't worry. I'm sure they can fly.
桃果といたあの日々だけが私の子供時代の全てだった（ほらほら　あっちあっち）
Look, look! Over there!
Those days I spent with Momoka were my world during childhood.
僕もだよ
Same goes for me.
たとえ　理不尽に命を奪われたとしても桃果は僕らに復讐など望まないはずだ
Even if her life was unfairly stolen away,
Momoka wouldn't want us to seek revenge.
桃果は死んでなんかいないわ
Momoka is not dead.
そうだったね
Right.
This room is so cold.
寒いわ　この部屋
カーテンが必要ね
We need curtains.
痺れるだろう
Isn't it electrifying?
人間の世界では　真実は必ずしも本当の事じゃない
In the human world, truth and reality aren't always one and the same.
人間は自分の見たい願望や欲望だけを真実という
Humans just call their desires and ambitions as "truth."
人間は真実が口実になれば　人だって殺せるんだ
Humans will even kill other humans if they have "truth" as excuse.
War. It's war.
戦争だよ　戦争　もうすぐ戦争が始まる
The war is about to break out.
困りましたね
This is bad.
It's time for her medicine.
お薬の時間なんですけどね
ちょっとお買いものに行ってきます
I'm going out for shopping.
すぐに帰ります　ひまり
I'll back right away.
From Himari.
ったく　何考えてるんだ　少しよくなったからって
Damn it, what was she thinking?
Just because she's a little better now...
Um...
あのう
It'll be bad
まずいですね
夜には予定の投薬をしないと
if she doesn't get her scheduled dose by tonight.
Um...
あのう　それをしないと　どうなるんですか
What happens if she doesn't?
So, we just need to get Himari back by night?
夜までにひまりが戻ればいいんですね
If she returns, yes.
戻ればね
戻れればね
If she can return, yes.
ひまりにも携帯持たせとくんだった
We should've given her a cell phone, too!
This selfish behavior...
こんな勝手をされては
is going to cause problems with Dr. Sanetoshi's special treatment.
眞悧先生のスペシャールな治療に差し障りが出ますね
Let's go, Shoma.
行くぞ　晶馬
Huh?
I know where Himari is.
ひまりの居場所が分かった
Himari, are you really all right?
ひまりちゃん　本当に大丈夫
Tell me right away if you get tired.
疲れたらすぐに言ってね
I'm fine.
大丈夫　先生から　外出許可貰ってきたんだもん
The doctor gave me the permission to leave!
You're with me, too.
リンゴちゃんもいてくれるし　平気平気
I'll be just fine!
If you say so...
ならいいけど
I want to finish Kan and Sho's sweaters before I'm released from the hospital.
退院する前に冠ちゃんと晶ちゃんのセーター仕上げちゃいたいんだ
They secretly made me takoyaki a few days ago in my hospital room, too!
この間もね　病室で内緒でタコ焼き作ってくれたんだ
Oh!
They're always taking care of me.
私いつもお兄ちゃん達にしてもらってばかり
だからね　たまには　私が二人に何かしてあげたいんだ
So I want to do something for them for once.
Can you keep the sweaters a secret?
セーターの事内緒にしてくれる
Himari...
ひまりちゃん
Yes! Of course!
うん　もちろん
I was knitting one,
ちょっと編みかけてたのがあったんだけど
but it wasn't Kan's favorite color, as it turns out.
それを見せたら　冠ちゃんの好みの色じゃないんだって
I see.
そっか　じゃあ　色を選び直しね
So we're picking a new color.
I wonder what color Kanba likes.
冠葉君はどんな色が好きなのかな
As for Shoma, maybe this gloomy color?
晶馬君はやっぱりこのもやもやした感じの色とか
Ringo.
リンゴちゃん　性格占いじゃないんだよ
We're not guessing their personalities!
Right.
あ　そっか
Kanba, huh?
冠葉君か
Maybe camouflage-printed?
迷彩柄とか
Camouflage-printed?
迷彩
Huh? Is that my phone?
あれ　あたしの携帯かな
Yes?
はい
こんにちは
Hello.
百合　さん
Yuri?
I had so much fun last time.
この間はとても楽しかったわ
Let's go to a hot spring resort again sometime.
また二人で温泉でも行きましょうね
O-Okay...
I know it's sudden,
ね　突然だけど　今から会えないかしら
but can we meet up now?
Uh, I'm actually with a friend right now.
あ　でも　今友達も一緒で
A friend?
お友達
Yes.
はい　この間話したひまりちゃんです
It's Himari. I've been telling you about her.
高倉晶馬君の妹さんです
She's Shoma Takakura's little sister.
あら　いいわね
Oh!
That's perfect!
Huh?
え
Let's have a dinner with just the three of us.
なら　三人でお食事しましょう　また後で連絡するわね
I'll call you later.
The Takakuras' daughter.
高倉の娘
支配人
Manager.
Yes, Ms. Tokikago?
はい　時籠様
I'll take the most fabulous curtains you have.
こちらで一番ファビュラスなカーテンを頂くわ
ありがとうございます
Thank you for your patronage.
It's hopeless.
だめだ　新宿にある手芸店全部回ったけど
I checked every fabric store in Shinjuku, but she's nowhere to be found!
Drum
Washer
どこにもいないよ
Don't panic.
焦るな　お前はその足で吉祥寺を回れ
Go and check Kichijoji next.
What about you?
兄貴は
I'm in Ikebukuro.
俺は池袋だ
I'll check out Yozawaya next.
これから　ユザワヤに行ってみる
Okay.
分かった　じゃあ
Later.
"What you treasure the most will be lost."
一番大切なものが損なわれる
Damn it. Himari!
くそ　ひまり
Incoming Call
Hubby <3
Keiju Tabuki
Yuri, this is Shoma's little sister.
百合さん　こちらが晶馬君の妹さんで
You're Himari?
I'm Himari Takakura.
あなたがひまりちゃんね
あたしの友達　高倉ひまりさんです
I...
私　貴方のこと
Hate...
Gosh, I must crush her soon.
嫌だわ　早くすり潰さないと
What a coincidence!
あら　奇遇ね
You were shopping in the same store?
貴方もお買いもの
Thank you for the wonderful song last time.
この間は素敵な歌声をありがとう
You were a touch off key, though.
すこしピッチがずれていたようだけど
Your ears must be broken.
聞き違いね　私のピッチはいつも正しいの
I'm alway pitch perfect.
You're the only one who thinks that.
そう思うのはあなただけ
Sly foxes must be punished.
人を騙す　女狐には罰を与えないと
Oh, to be so young.
青いわね
A pure maiden who has never known a man can't even tell the difference between an imitation from the real deal.
男も知らない生娘だから　本物と偽物の区別もつかない
Gosh, parvenu celebrities have no class.
嫌だわ　成り上がりの芸能人は　下品で
Neither of us can back down.
お互い譲り合うことは
That is our destiny.
できないのは　私達の運命
To bring back Momoka to this world!
桃果を再びこの世界に取り戻すために
To save Mario's life!
マリオさんの命を救うために
Do you know why a pure maiden like you can't revolutionize your own world?
生娘はなぜ自分の世界を変革できないかご存知
I'm intrigued. Do tell.
おもしろそうだから　言ってみなさい
その若さが世間に消費されてすり潰されることを恐れているから
The fear of your innocence being consumed only allows you to see half of the world!
生娘の貴方には世界の半分しか見えない
You're past expiration, so you can only survive by selling yourself at a discount!
賞味期限が切れた貴方には　自分の人生をディスカウントするしか生きるすべはない
Cheap porn mags are waiting for you!
安いグラビアタッチがお呼びよ
For as long as you don't believe in yourself, your life will only be consumed!
貴方自身が自分を信じない限り　貴方の人生は消費されるだけ
Your life has already been consumed!
貴方の人生は既に　消費されたわ
Really? I can meet Yuri Tokikago?
へえ　時籠百合さんと会えるの
Yes. She invited us to dinner over phone, just now.
うん
さっきの電話　三人で御飯でもどうかって
Wow!
すごい
わ　私もいっていいの
Is it really okay for me to come?
うん　百合さん　すごく喜んでた
Yuri was really happy about it.
Maybe because I told her you were a huge fan.
ひまりちゃんが大ファンだって言ったからかな
ありがとう　リンゴちゃん
Thank you, Ringo!
But don't you have to go back to the hospital?
でも　まだ病院に帰らなくていいの
I'll be fine.
大丈夫　まだ時間あるから
I still have time.
More importantly, what's Ms. Yuri like?
それより　百合さんってどんな人
What's she like?
どんな人
Uh...
えっと
She's a very nice person.
とても素敵な人だよ
Yeah, nothing on my end either.
ああ　こっちも空振りだ
I was told there were countless girls who came to shop alone.
店員に聞いたら
一人で毛糸を買っていた女の子なんて山ほどいるってさ
What about you?
そっちはどうだ
She's not back yet.
帰ってきませんね
Nope.
来ませんね
Bad girl.
だめな子です
Naughty girl.
悪い子です
Bad, naughty girls must be punished.
だめな悪い子には罰を与えないと
Yes. Terribly punished.
そう　大きな罰を
Isn't it frightening?
怖いですね
怖いです
It sure is.
Um, are we really meeting Yuri up here?
あの　本当にこの上で百合さんと待ち合わせなんですか
I can't wait to meet Yuri Tokikago! She's my heroine.
憧れの百合さんに会えるなんて　ドキドキしちゃうな
ねえ　リンゴちゃん
Hey, Ringo.
Y-Yes?
あっ　はい
Do you remember what I told you before?
前に僕が話したこと覚えてる
Huh?
Everything has a meaning no matter how sad and painful it may be.
どんな辛いこと　悲しいことにも必ず意味がある
Nothing in this world is pointless.
無駄なことなんて一つもない
Yes, I remember.
はい　それなら
That's good to hear.
それは良かった
I invited you here because there's something I wanted you to know.
ここに招待したのはね
実は君たちにぜひ知っておいてほしいことがあるからなんだ
Something you wanted us to know?
知っておいてほしいこと
Yes.
そう　僕の生きている　意味
The meaning of my life.
I will show you.
これから見せてあげる
I've made up my mind.
決めたんだ
Tabu...ki?
多蕗　さん
Today, I shall hand down the punishment to the Takakura Family.
今日僕は高倉家の人間に罰を与えるよ
The Unforgiven
kuroi yokan ga  chikazuite kuru
Bad news is drawing near
黒い予感が　近づいてくる
kutsu wo hibikase  sunakemuri tate
Footsteps echo and kick up clouds of dust
靴を響かせ　砂煙立て
warui yume ga  tsuzuku to omotteta
I thought the nightmare would last forever
悪い夢が　続くと思ってた
yake ni hageshiku  kaze ga fukiareta
An awfully violent wind blew by
やけに激しく風が吹き荒れた
hi ga nobori  hi ga shizumu
The sun rises and the sun sinks
陽が上り　陽が沈む
shizuka datta hibi ga kieru
The quiet days have vanished
静かだった　日々が消える
omae omou  yoru ga aru kedo
There are nights when I think about you, but
お前思う　夜があるけど
searchlight ga  tsukenerau
The searchlights are on the prowl
サーチライトがつけ狙う
achikochi de coup d'étas ga okoridasu
Coup d'étas are springing up every which where
あちこちで　クーデターが起り出す
achikochi de coup d'étas ga okoridasu
Coup d'étas are springing up every which where
あちこちで　クーデターが起り出す
darou
Right...
だろう
darou
Right...
だろう
darou
Right...
だろう
darou
Right...
だろう
Please stop.
もうやめて　私分かってるよ
I know already.
So, stop suffering because of me.
だからもうこれ以上私のために苦しまないで
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy. I love takoyaki.
生存戦略　たこ焼き好きよね